Guide to the Zalba-Hollister Bakery Records, 1907-1925
Department of Special Collections
Zalba-Hollister Bakery Records,
1907-1925
Special Collections M0160
Zalba-Hollister Bakery.
3.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. William Hart, 1967.
Biographical Note
Mrs. Estephania Zalba came to the United States in the 1890's. She married Frank (Francisco) Zalba [second husband?] and after his death [ca. 1920?] ran the business with her nephew. She died in the early 1940's.
Scope and Content
The Zalba collection includes the business history of a bakery operated by Basques in Hollister, California. They catered to the local Basques, performing services such as finding them employment in the mines and loaning them money. They also provided supplies for the mines at New Idria.
Oversize photo to Special Collections, 43 issues of Las Novedades, a Spanish Language newspaper published in New York to Newspaper Reading Room More material - photos being used by George P. Kane
Container List
- Correspondence 1907 and 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence 1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence 1919 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Check Stubs - Frank Zalba 1909-14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Check Stubs - Frank Zalba 1914-19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Check Stubs - Zalba & Co. 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Check Stubs - Zalba & Co. 1912-1914 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Check Stubs - Zalba & Co. 1914-1916 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Check Stubs - Zalba & Co. 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Check Stubs - Zalba & Astiz 1915-1917 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Check Stubs - Zalba & Astiz 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Check Stubs - Zalba & Ozcoidi 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Check Stubs - Zalba & Larrey 1924 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Check Stubs -misc. & [savings acct.].passbooks (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Bank Statements- Frank Zalba- Aug. 1917 - Sept. 1919 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Bank Statements- Zalba & Astia [Dec. 1917-1918] (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Bank Statements- Zalba & Ozcoidi Dec. 1918 - Sept. 1919 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Bank Statements- Zalba & Co. Aug. 1917 - Apr. 1918, Aug. 1918 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Bank Statements- Zalba & Larrey 1923-25 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Bank Statements- [Estephania] Zalba 1923 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Bills Rendered 1912-19 & n.d. (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Sales Books Apr. 25 - June 1, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Sales Slips Feb. - Mar. 1925 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Sales Slips Mar. - Apr. 1925 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Accounts Receivable 1909-11 (Box 4, Volume Vol. 28)
- Accounts Receivable 1909-11 (Box 5, Volume Vol. 29)
- Accounts Receivable 1912-15 (Volume Mss Codex M0160f, Volume Vol. 30)
- Expenses 1910-13, 1923-24, 1924-25 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Expenses 1910-15 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Expenses 1915-18 (Volume Vol. 33)
- Expenses 1918-19 (Box 6, Volume V. 34)
- Accounts Received 1910-13 &laundry or linen supply list (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Misc. Ledger (Box 6, Volume V. 36)
- Misc. Financial Records & notes (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Cash or Day Book 1910-12 (Box 6, Volume V. 38)
- Bills Payable (some receipted) 1904, 1911, 12, 14-16 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Bills Payable (some receipted) 1917-18 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Bills Payable (some receipted) 1919, Jan.-June (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Bills Payable (some receipted) 1919, July-Dec. (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Bills Payable (some receipted) 1923-25 & n.d. (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Gen. Business & Financial Papers (Box 7, Folder 44)
  inventories, contracts, agreements, bills of lading receipts, financial orders, drafts, examples of checks, credit memos, taxes and licenses, (including marriage license)
- Business & Financial - Misc. (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Order Books (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Misc. - political flyers, subscription books, recipes, part of play in (Sp?) (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Photos, postcards, cook books, autograph album (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Accounts Receivable 1918-19 (Box 8)